Guide to the Benson J. Lossing Papers, 1861-1956
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
- SERIES VIII. MEMORABILIA, 1723-1979
  - Pamphlets
    - Vassar College: Its Foundation, Aims, Resources, and Course of Study, 1873; (78 p.) (Folder 7.1)
    - A Memorial Paper on the Life of Nathan Bishop, LL.D. by S.S. Constant, 1880; (24 p.) (Folder 7.2)
    - Last Will and Testament of Matthew Vassar Jr., Signed, 1881; (10 p.) (Folder 7.3)
    - Americana: the Library of the late Benson Lossing, American Historian; Part II: Books and Letters, A-K, Anderson Auction Company, 1912; (127 p.) (Folder 7.4)
    - Americana: the Library of the late Benson Lossing, American Historian; Part II: Books and Letters, L-Z, Anderson Auction Company, 1912; (262 p.) (Folder 7.5)
    - Americana: the Library of the late Benson Lossing, American Historian; Part III: Autographs, Prints, Broadsides, Anderson Auction Company, 1912; (60 p.) (Folder 7.6)
  - Miscellaneous Memorabilia
    - Historical material re: tax payments, etc., Lossing family connections, 1723-1830; (4 items) (Folder 7.7)
    - Administrative bond: The King vs. S. Dorland and Jacobus Swartwout, 1770; (2 items) (Folder 7.8)
    - Advertisement: Lossing and Barritt, Designers and Engravers on Wood, undated; (2 items) (Folder 7.9)
    - Name cards; Matthew Vassar's autographs; envelopes, undated; (4 items) (Folder 7.10)
    - VC Founder's Day invitation and program, 1866-1867; (2 items) (Folder 6.23)
    - VC Music Department invitations, 1866-1868; (3 items) (Folder 6.24)
    - VC Music Department programs, 1868-1890; (10 items) (Folder 6.25)
    - VC Trustees' Dinner program (annotated by Lossing), 1861; (1 item) (Folder 6.26)
    - Young Ladies' Academy, Ursuline Convent, Quebec prospectus, undated; (1 item) (Folder 6.27)
  - Newspaper Articles
    - "Early History of Dutchess County;" source: unknown [written by Lossing?], 1854; (1 item) (Folder 6.28)
    - "Death of Professor Orton" [in Dutchess Forum], 1877; (1 item) (Folder 6.29)
    - "Matthew Vassar's Will" and "The Charities of Matthew Vassar" [sources unknown], circa 1881; (2 items) (Folder 6.30)
    - Articles re: Vassar College Presidency, circa 1885; (3 items) (Folder 6.31)
    - "A Presentation to Vassar College;" [in Daily Eagle ], 1888; (1 item) (Folder 6.32)
    - "The Gossip Tells Some Unpublished Authentic Anecdotes of Abraham Lincoln" [interview with Lossing in Philadelphia Daily News ], 1890; (4 items) (Folder 6.33)
    - "Lossing, Benson John" [in Guide to American Historical Manuscripts in the Huntington Library ], 1979; (1 item) (Folder 6.34)
    - "John Guy Vassar's Estate" [source unknown], undated; (1 item) (Folder 6.35)
    - "Vassar's Start" [in Brooklyn Eagle], undated; (1 item) (Folder 6.36)
    - "Women to Teach Women" [annotated by Lossing, source unknown], undated; (1 item, oversized) (Folder 8.7)
  - Pamphlets
    - "Vassar College: Its Foundation, Aims, Resources, and Course of Study,", 1873; (78 p.) (Folder 7.1)
    - "A Memorial Paper on the Life of Nathan Bishop, LL.D." by S.S. Constant, 1880; (24 p.) (Folder 7.2)
    - Last Will and Testament of Matthew Vassar Jr., Signed, 1881; (10 p.) (Folder 7.3)
    - "Americana: the Library of the late Benson Lossing, American Historian; Part II: Books and Letters, A-K," Anderson Auction Company, 1912; (127 p.) (Folder 7.4)
    - "Americana: the Library of the late Benson Lossing, American Historian; Part II: Books and Letters, L-Z," Anderson Auction Company, 1912; (262 p.) (Folder 7.5)
    - "Americana: the Library of the late Benson Lossing, American Historian; Part III: Autographs, Prints, Broadsides," Anderson Auction Company, 1912; (60 p.) (Folder 7.6)
  - Miscellaneous Memorabilia
    - Historical material re: tax payments, etc., Lossing family connections, 1723-1830; (4 items) (Folder 7.7)
    - Administrative bond: The King vs. S. Dorland and Jacobus Swartwout, 1770; (2 items) (Folder 7.8)
    - Advertisement: Lossing and Barritt, Designers and Engravers on Wood, undated; (2 items) (Folder 7.9)
    - Name cards; Matthew Vassar's autographs; envelopes, undated; (4 items) (Folder 7.10)